在这第一节课中，我们将探讨
In this first lesson, we'll go
Claude Code 的代理化工作流，
through the agentic workflow of Claude Code,
它在导航代码库时使用的工具，
the tools it uses to navigate your codebase,
以及它在跨会话中保持的记忆。让我们开始吧。
and the memory it keeps across sessions. Let's dive in.
首先，让我们聊聊 Claude Code 究竟是什么。
So let's talk a little bit about what Claude Code actually is.
当我们谈论代理系统时，
When we talk about agentic systems,
我们通常会联想到一个模型、一组工具，
we think a lot about a model, a set of tools,
以及运行这些工具的环境。
and some environment to run those tools.
模型擅长处理输入并返回输出。
Models are great at handling input and returning output.
但在许多情况下，这些模型并不了解你的代码库，
But in many situations, those models don't know about your codebase,
不知道如何查找文件，也不知道如何处理多个任务。
how to find files, and how to handle multiple tasks.
因此，我们不直接与模型对话，
So instead of just talking directly to a model,
而是为该模型提供一个非常轻量级的“外壳”（Harness）。
we're going to provide a very lightweight harness for that model.
通过命令行，我们将
And through the command line, we're going to
利用这个外壳来发挥模型的智能，
use that harness to leverage the model's intelligence
从而执行复杂的编程任务。
to perform complex coding tasks.
所以，我们不是直接把任务交给模型
So instead of giving a task directly to the model
并让它在代码库中费力地搜索各种信息。
and trying to find all kinds of information in a codebase.
我们将提供一套工具。
We're going to provide a set of tools.
我们将提供一个环境
We're going to provide an environment
以及其他一些功能，
and a couple other pieces of functionality
以使模型能够
to enable the model
梳理代码库并解决更复杂的问题。
to come through codebases and solve much more complex problems.
我们谈论的这些功能具体指什么呢？
What are those pieces of functionality that we're talking about here?
包括赋予模型记忆能力，
Enabling the model to have memory,
让我们的模型能够记住用户的偏好、
enabling our model here to remember preferences of the user
正在查看的代码库或当前的任务。
and the codebase we're going through or the task at hand.
我们还为模型提供一个环境，
also going to give the model an environment
让它能自主搞清楚需要什么数据、
where it can figure out what data it needs,
制定计划并采取行动。
formulate a plan and then take action.
只需少量的代码，
With just a small amount of code,
我们就可以利用模型的智能来取得非常显著的效果。
we can leverage the model's intelligence to achieve quite remarkable results.
在使用 Claude Code 时，你的选择
With Claude Code, your options
有 Opus 或 Sonnet，取决于任务的复杂程度、
are Opus or Sonnet, depending on the complexity,
任务类型以及你的订阅情况。
the kind of task you're handling, and your subscription.
当我们谈论 Claude Code 能做什么时，
When we talk about what Claude Code can do,
很容易认为这只是一个
it's very tempting to just think this is the tool for
用来编写大量代码的工具。但随着课程的进行，
for writing lots of code. But as we progress in this course,
我们将从 Claude Code 最强大的功能之一开始，
we're actually going to start with one of the most powerful features
那就是它的
of Claude Code, which is its ability
发现、解释和设计能力。
to discover, explain, and design.
在你开始用 Claude Code 编写代码之前，
Before you start writing code with Claude Code,
可以用它来
use it as a way to get
快速熟悉一个代码库。
up to speed on a code base.
我们会讨论很多关于用 Claude Code 编写代码的内容，
We'll talk quite a bit about writing code with Claude Code,
但也会讨论在终端之外（如 GitHub 等环境）
but we'll also talk about ways in which you can use it
使用它的方法。我们还会聊聊
outside of the terminal in environments like GitHub. We'll talk a bit
重构、调试错误，
bit about refactoring, debugging errors
以及这个工具真正大放异彩的地方。
and where this tool really shines.
它不仅对编程有用，
Not only is this useful for coding,
也适用于数据分析和任何
but also across data analysis and any environment
可以利用模型智能来创建引人入胜的
where the model's intelligence can create compelling
可视化效果、资产或交付物的环境。
visualizations, assets or deliverables for you.
我们提到过给模型一个“外壳”。
We mentioned that we give the model a harness.
我们给模型一个环境
We give the model an environment
来收集上下文并采取行动。
to gather context and take an action.
我们聊到了
We talked a bit about the
提供给模型的记忆。
memory that we provide to the model.
稍后，我们将讨论
And in a little bit, we'll talk
底层记忆的具体形式。
about what that underlying memory looks like.
现在，让我们聊聊工具，
Now, let's talk about the tools
或者说我们让模型了解的附加功能。
or additional functionality that we let the model know about.
为了说明工具的使用，
To give an illustration of tool use,
你可以想象用户询问
you can imagine that the user asks
某个特定文件中写了什么代码。
what code is written in a particular file.
模型本身并不知道如何导航或
The model does not know how to navigate or
查找文件，这就是工具调用（Tool Use）发挥作用的地方。
find files, and that's where tool use comes into play.
开箱即用的 Claude Code
Out of the box, Claude Code
提供了一个相对精简的
provides a relatively small list of
工具列表。其中之一就是
tools. One of those being the ability
读取文件的能力。现在模型知道该做什么了，
to read a file. Now that the model knows what to do,
它可以去读取那个文件，
it can go ahead and read that file,
获取文件的内容，
get the contents of that file,
并将数据返回给用户。
and return the data to a user.
这种工具调用的能力使模型能够
This ability of tool use allows the model to go
从一个简单的助手转变为极其先进的代理工具。
from a simple assistant to an extremely sophisticated agentic tool.
我们提到了 Claude Code
We mentioned some of the tools
内置的一些工具。
that Claude Code comes built in with.
这是我们的工具列表。
Here is a list of the tools that we have.
其中一些用于跨不同类型的文件进行编辑；
Some of those for editing across different kinds of files.
一些用于读取不同的文件；
Some of those for reading across different files.
还有一些用于执行额外操作，
and some for doing additional actions
比如寻找模式、
like finding patterns,
网页搜索，
searching things across the web,
甚至创建或运行子代理
and even creating or running sub-agents
来处理非常困难和具有挑战性的任务。
to handle very difficult and challenging tasks.
最后，因为我们在命令行中，
Finally, since we're in the command line,
我们需要一个执行 Bash 或 Shell 命令的工具。
we're going to need a tool to execute bash or shell commands.
工具调用让 Claude Code 能够
Tool use is what allows Claude Code
收集所需的上下文和信息。
to gather the context and information that it needs.
这使得 Claude Code 能够解决更困难的问题。
This allows Claude Code to tackle harder problems.
它还使得 Claude Code
It also allows Claude Code
无需索引你的整个代码库，
to not have to index your entire code base
从而避免了潜在的安全风险。
and lead into potential security concerns.
最后，Claude Code 的扩展性很强。
Finally, Claude Code is quite extensible.
虽然你刚才看到了 Claude Code
While you just saw the list of tools
内置的工具列表，
that Claude Code comes built in with,
你还可以通过连接 MCP 服务器
you can also add additional tools
来添加更多工具。
by connecting to MCP servers.
MCP，即模型上下文协议（Model Context Protocol），
MCP, or the model context protocol,
是一个开源的、与模型无关的协议，
is an open-source model agnostic protocol
它允许数据和 AI 系统轻松通信。
that allows for data and AI systems to communicate easily.
这些 MCP 服务器可以
These MCP servers can
为 Claude Code 添加功能，
add functionality to Claude Code
以应对各种不同的任务，
for a variety of different tasks
我们将在本课程中探索其中的一些。
and we'll explore a few of them over this course.
我想再花点时间
I want to take a little more time to
谈谈“不索引代码库”到底是什么意思。
talk about what we mean by not indexing a codebase.
Claude Code 不是创建代码库的结构化表示
Instead of creating a structured representation of the codebase
并不断对其进行分析，
and constantly analyzing that,
而是使用一种名为“代理化搜索”（Agentic Search）的功能。
Claude Code instead uses a feature called agentic search.
它不需要将代码库发送到服务器，
Instead of requiring that that codebase is sent to a server
从而可能离开你所在的生态系统，
and potentially leaving the ecosystem that you're in,
Claude Code 而是使用
Claude Code instead uses
一个或多个不同的代理和工具集，
one or many different agents and sets of tools
在你的代码库中寻找它想要的内容。
to find what it's looking for in your codebase.
这使得你的代码不必
This allows your code to not
完全加入上下文，
have to be completely added to context
或者必须离开它所在的生态系统，
or to have to leave the ecosystem that it's in,
这解决了一些安全方面的顾虑。
which can create certain security considerations.
当我们谈论 Claude 的记忆，或者它记住
When we talk about the memory of Claude or its ability
之前对话发生的事情，
to remember what has happened in previous conversations
或者各种操作的
or across all kinds of
能力时，这是通过一个名为
actions. This is done using a markdown file
claude.md 的 Markdown 文件实现的。
called claude.md
在你的 claude.md 文件中，你可以定义通用配置
In your claude.md file, you can define common configurations
或风格指南。
or style guidelines.
这些文件在启动时会
These files get automatically loaded
自动加载到上下文中。
into context when launched.
你与 Claude Code 的对话内容
The conversation that you have with claude code
存储在你的本地机器上。
is stored locally on your machine.
你可以在对话过程中清除它，
You can clear that over the course of a conversation,
这样你就可以开启一个新的上下文窗口。
so you can start with a new context window.
但如果出于某种原因，你需要继续
But if for some reason, you need to continue
之前的对话，或者恢复
that previous one or resume the
早些时候的交流，也可以轻松实现。
earlier conversation, you can do so easily.
现在我要去
I'm going to head over to the
我在 VS Code 内部打开的终端。
terminal that I have inside of VS Code.
我们可以看到我这里有一个
And we can see I have a
名为 demo 的文件夹，里面什么都没有。
folder here called demo with nothing in it.
首先，让我们使用 claude 命令打开 Claude Code。
So let's start by opening up Claude Code using the claude command.
取决于文件位置，尤其是第一次运行时，
Depending on where this file is, and especially the first time,
它可能会问我是否信任
it may ask if I trust the
该文件夹中的文件，我选择信任。
files in this folder, which I do.
这里有一些不错的入门提示，
We've gotten a couple nice tips here for getting
但我将从一个简单的提示词开始。
started, but I'm just going to start with a very simple prompt.
为我做一个酷炫的可视化效果。
Make a cool visualization for me.
我只是刚刚开始。我们
I'm just getting started. What we're
将在这里看到 Claude Code
going to see here is Claude Code
开始制定一份要执行的操作待办清单。
start to make a to-do list of actions to take.
你可以想象，这个任务可能是搜索代码库、
You can imagine this task might be to search across a codebase,
编辑文件、编写测试、提供洞察，
to edit files, to write tests, to deliver insights,
或者是像我们这种情况，创建一个可视化效果。
or in our case to create a visualization.
根据 Claude 的“心情”，
Depending on how Claude is feeling,
这可能是粒子、烟花或者其他效果，
this might be particles or fireworks or something else,
但我只想向你展示，
but I just want to show you how quickly
开箱即用的 Claude Code
out of the box you can
能以多快的速度让你看到变化。
start to see changes with Claude Code.
因为我们是在 Visual Studio Code 中操作的，
Since we're doing this inside of Visual Studio Code
而且 Claude Code 与该编辑器有集成，
and Claude Code has an integration with that editor,
我们将直观地看到正在进行的更改。
we're going to see visually the changes that are being made.
我会接受这些更改，而且在以后的版本中，
I'll accept those and in future editions,
我会让 Claude Code 直接操作，而不再向我请求许可。
I'll let Claude Code do that without requesting permission from me.
我们可以看到，可视化效果已经构建好了。
We can see here, we have a visualization that's built.
让我们直接在浏览器中打开它。
Let's go ahead and open it in the browser.
我会让 Claude Code 帮我
I'll ask Claude Code to do that for
操作。它会确认。这就是具体的命令。
me. It will confirm. This is the command.
让我们去看看它长什么样。
Let's go see what it looks like.
瞧，这就是我们的可视化效果。
And here we are with our visualization.
可以添加一些粒子。
Can add some particles.
看起来好多了。你可以切换动画，
lookin' a bit better. You can toggle the animation,
查看运行情况，并清除当前内容。
see what's going on, and clear what we have here.
我们可以根据需要对它进行任意扩展。
We can expand on this as much as we want.
我们可以更改功能，
We can change the functionality, we
在这里添加任何我们想要的内容。
can add whatever we want right here.
但我只是想向你展示，
But I just want to show you
这个工具开箱即用是多么无缝，
out of the box how seamless it is
上手运行是多么简单。
to get up and running with this particular tool.
在下一课中，我们将探讨如何
In the next lesson, we'll explore how
在更大的代码库中使用 Claude Code，
to use Claude Code across a larger codebase
并退一步看看它是多么强大，
and take a step back and see just how powerful it is
尤其是在解释更大、更复杂的代码库方面。
for explaining larger and more complex code bases.